{"test_questions": [[{"question": "A molecular technique in which DNA sequences between two oligonucleotide primers can be amplified is known as", "opta": "southern blotting", "optb": "northern blotting", "optc": "polymerase chain reaction", "optd": "DNA replication", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Southern blotting technique depends on", "opta": "similarities between the sequences of probe DNA and experimental DNA", "optb": "similarities between the sequences of probe RNA and experimental RNA", "optc": "similarities between the sequences of probe protein and experimental protein", "optd": "the molecular mass of proteins", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Problems in obtaining large amounts of proteins encoded by recombinant genes can often be overcome by using", "opta": "BACS", "optb": "expression vectors", "optc": "YACS", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Agrobacterium tumefaciens is", "opta": "a disease in humans that causes loss of sight", "optb": "a bacterium that can be used to introduce DNA into plants", "optc": "a fungi that is used to produce antibiotics in large amounts", "optd": "a disease in humans that causes loss of weight", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In genetic engineering, a chimera is", "opta": "an enzyme that links DNA molecules", "optb": "a plasmid that contains foreign DNA", "optc": "a virus that infects bacteria", "optd": "a fungi", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The deliberate modifications of an organism's genetic information by directly changing its nucleic acid content is a subject matter of", "opta": "genetic engineering", "optb": "population genetics", "optc": "microbiology", "optd": "protein engineering", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electroporation is", "opta": "the process of separating charged molecules through a gel maintained in an electric field", "optb": "the process of combining foreign DNA to an electrically charged vector molecule", "optc": "the application of high voltage pulses", "optd": "the process of multiplication of the cells", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is obtained using processed mRNA molecules as a template?", "opta": "rDNA", "optb": "mDNA", "optc": "cDNA", "optd": "tDNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vectors are", "opta": "molecules that degrade nucleic acids", "optb": "molecules that help in replication", "optc": "molecules that are able to covalently bond to and carry foreign DNA into cells", "optd": "molecules that protect host cells from invasion by foreign DNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the normal role of restriction endonucleases in bacterial cells?", "opta": "To degrade the bacterial chromosome into small pieces during replication", "optb": "To degrade invading phage DNA", "optc": "To produce RNA primers for replication", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not commonly used as vector?", "opta": "Artificial chromosome", "optb": "Cosmid", "optc": "Fungi", "optd": "Plasmid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A short molecule containing 2-20 nucleotide is", "opta": "plasmid", "optb": "vector", "optc": "oligonucleotide", "optd": "mononucleotide", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enzymes that recognize and cleave specific 4 to 8 base pair sequences of DNA are", "opta": "DNA ligase", "optb": "helicases", "optc": "restriction endonucleases", "optd": "DNA gyrase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following vector can maintain the largest fragment of foreign DNA?", "opta": "YAC", "optb": "Cosmid", "optc": "Plasmid", "optd": "Phage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Charged molecules are separated based on varying rates of migration through a solid matrix when subjected to an electric field. This technique is known as", "opta": "photoreactivation", "optb": "gel electrophoresis", "optc": "autoradiography", "optd": "blotting", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For gene probes to be useful they must", "opta": "be large enough to contain gene-specific sequences", "optb": "be labeled in some manner to allow detection", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A genomic library is", "opta": "a database where the sequence of an organism's genome is stored", "optb": "a collection of many clones possessing different DNA fragments from the same organisms bound to vectors", "optc": "a book that describes how to isolate DNA from a particular organism", "optd": "a place where the information of the genetic organization of organisms are kept.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following enzyme is used to covalently bond foreign DNA to a vector plasmid?", "opta": "DNA polymerase", "optb": "Restriction endonuclease", "optc": "DNA ligase", "optd": "DNA helicase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacterial cells protect their own DNA from degradation by restriction endonucleases by", "opta": "methylating the DNA at the sites that the enzyme recognizes", "optb": "deleting all recognition sites from the genome", "optc": "not producing any restriction endonucleases", "optd": "having anti restriction endonucleases", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of restriction endonuclease cuts the DNA within the recognition site?", "opta": "Type I", "optb": "Type II", "optc": "Type III", "optd": "All of the these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The piece of equipment, that introduces DNA into cells via DNA-coated microprojectiles is known as", "opta": "laser", "optb": "DNA probe", "optc": "gene gun", "optd": "inoculating needle", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An animal, that has gained new genetic information from the acquisition of foreign DNA, is considered as", "opta": "a chimera", "optb": "a transgenic animal", "optc": "a vector", "optd": "an enzyme that links DNA molecules", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The advantage of using DNA polymerases from thermophilic organisms in PCR is that", "opta": "the DNA polymerases of these bacteria are much faster than those from other organisms", "optb": "the DNA polymerases of these bacteria can withstand the high temperatures needed to denature the DNA strands", "optc": "the DNA polymerases of these bacteria never make mistakes while replicating DNA", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}